## Andrew Nicholson

(540) 728-0119 nicholsonsoftware@gmail.com https://github.com/anicholson44

#### Personal Mission Statement

To advocate for best practices that serve the customer, to use my expertise to solve complex and strategic problems, to own and drive product success, to mentor and help others achieve their goals, and ultimately to make lives better with the products my team creates.

## Work Experience

Founding Engineer / Staff Software Engineer at Rula Mental Health December 2021 - March 2024, remote \* Joined as engineer #3 \* Built foundational services and products, including a resilient email system, partnership integrations, and web portal products for both patients and therapists \* Drove cross-functional initiatives including a process to develop an SDLC and an org-wide reference architecture based on Domain-Driven Design, Event-Driven Architecture, and Command/Query Responsibility Segregation \* Implemented a Transactional Outbox and Durable Workflow Execution Environment to provide the team with solutions to widespread distributed systems problems

#### Staff Software Engineer at Sift

January 2021 - December 2021, remote \* Joined through the **2021 acquisition** of ChargeBack \* Designed and led development of a new data architecture to enable flexible product support for customers, unblocking business scalability \* Worked closely with product managers to shape our low-code business rules platform

# Senior Full-Stack React/Ruby on Rails Engineer and Team Lead at Spatial Networks

March 2020 - December 2020, remote \* Led development and took ownership over project success for a strategic low-code platform feature using Ruby on Rails, React, and Postgresql \* Provided technical leadership and mentorship in the company's product-focused engineering team \* Advocated for industry best practices around DevSecOps and drove a cultural shift to adopt new processes in line with those best practices, including Kanban, automated testing, and CI/CD

#### Full-Stack React/C# Engineer at Pluralsight, LLC

November 2018 – November 2019 in Salt Lake City, UT and remote \* Joined

throught the 2019 acquisition of GitPrime, Inc. \* Delivered high-visibility, strategic integration between GitPrime and Pluralsight \* Engineered web applications with TypeScript, React, Redux, C#, and PostgreSQL

Full-Stack React/Ruby on Rails Developer at SciMed Solutions, Inc. February 2016 – November 2018 in Durham, NC and remote \* Engineered web applications for clients in agricultural and medical research \* Consistently delivered high-quality software for SciMed's biggest clients using React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, and SQL databases

#### Full-Stack JEE Developer at Red Hat, Inc.

August 2013 – June 2015 in Richmond, VA and remote \* Contributed to high priority projects \* Mentored junior developers

#### Software Developer Intern at Noblis, Inc.

June 2012 – January 2013 in Danville, VA and remote \* **Led development** of a Grails web application that displayed results from computations run on a Cray XMT2 supercomputer

# Technical Expertise

TypeScript, Ruby on Rails, Node, React, AMQP, Kafka, Postgres, AWS, CI/CD

# Education

University of Virginia, College of Arts and Sciences, Charlottesville, VA August 2009 – May 2013 BA in Computer Science and Philosophy